Joao Costa

New York, NY 10009 | Phone: 917 306 1291 | Email: costa.16@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joao-costa-919535193/

Github: https://github.com/jCosta16

Data Analyst / Business Analyst who enjoys acquiring new knowledge and facing new challenges. Fast learner and good problem-solver with great team and leadership abilities. Experienced in working with executive staff and promoting collaboration across different parts of an organization. Holds knowledge in Agile methodology and Python, MySQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Tableau and Machine Learning skills.

No work Visa sponsorship needed.

Technical Skills

Tools: Python, VBA, JavaScript, Mongo, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, D3, Tableau, Machine Learning

Projects

Caixa Habitacao APP

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=br.gov.caixa.habitacao&hl=en US

- APP that offers services for clients with House Loan Contracts.
- Product Owner, User Tester and Requirement approval.
- API (JSON, XLM), SCRUM
- Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=br.gov.caixa.habitacao&hl=en_US

Soccer Dashboard

- An application that uses scraped data about Brazil and US soccer leagues to build a dashboard with information about players, teams and their market values.
- Python, BeautifulSoup, SQL (PostgreSQL), Tableau, JSON, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, D3
- Project Link: https://jcosta16.github.io/soccer/
- Github Link: https://github.com/jCosta16/Soccer Dashboard

Breast Cancer Diagnosis using Machine Learning

- Cancer Diagnosis using Machine Learning.
- Python, scikit-learn, keras, Matplotlib
- Project Link: https://jcosta16.github.io/cancer-webpage/
- GithubLink: https://github.com/jCosta16/MachineLearning_cancer_diagnosis

Relevant Experience

Product Owner/ Team Member

2017 - 2018

Caixa Economica Federal (Bank)

Brasília, Brazil

Used critical thinking to manage the backlog for projects, as well as produced Business Requirement Documents and reviewed Functional Requirement Documents for projects. Tested and approved functionalities, with special attention to details. Worked in different projects at same time with great teamwork capacity. Used leadership and team work skills to promote collaboration across different teams and parts of the organization.

Key Accomplishments:

- Participated actively in the development of "Caixa Habitação APP". Allowing more than 3 million potential users to access services for their Housing Loan contracts on their phones.
- Developed Housing Loan contracts solutions for Online Banking.
- Awards: 2017 Best Project VP of Housing Loan

Senior Consultant | Corporate Caixa Economica Federal (Bank)

2016 – 2018 Brasília, Brazil

Worked with research and analytical skills to produce technical studies on market trend analysis, in order to propose improvement of existing products and services and development of new ones. Coordinated and promoted improvement regarding systems and processes, set up scenarios to develop awareness through SWOT analysis. Provided information and developed solutions regarding products and services of the company supporting decision making.

Additional Experience

Regional Operations Supervisor Caixa Economica Federal (Bank)

2014 – 2016

Brasília, Brazil

Working with real estate construction financing for companies, supervised the operational work involved in processing real estate financing contracts. With critical thinking identified opportunities and applied product knowledge to offer the right product to customers. Collaborate with different areas of the company, aiming to solve problems and deliver a better customer experience.

Operations Housing Loan Supervisor Caixa Economica Federal (Bank)

2012 – 2014

Brasília, Brazil

Oversaw the operational work involved in processing Housing Loan contracts.

Housing Loan Analyst Caixa Economica Federal (Bank)

2011 – 2012

Brasília, Brazil

Coordinated operational work involved in processing Housing Loan contracts.

Education

Columbia University Certificate Data Analytics: New York City, NY

Graduate Degree in Accounting and Finance, UDF, Brasília, Brazil.

Bachelor of Science in Accounting and Finance, Universidade de Brasília, Brasília, Brazil.